进展如何
How's it coming?
非常  非常好
Ah. Very, very well.
拆包裹拆到手软
It's a flurry of deliveries.
有种圣诞节早上拆礼物的感觉
Feels like Christmas morning.
真令人兴奋
Ah, it's exciting.
进展神速
It's really coming together.
有一件事我想说明
And I would like to point out
如果您对采购价格有任何疑问
that if you have any very understandable questions
那是非常可以理解的
about the price tag...
这声响  就是品质
That sound... quality.
辉瑞公司  默克公司[美国著名制药公司]
At Pfizer, at Merck,
用的都是这东西
that unit would be right at home.
所有设备都是这样
That goes for all of it.
很好
Good.
我希望你拿到你所需要的
I want you to have what you need.
先生  我向您致以崇高的敬意
Oh. Well, I doff my proverbial cap to you, sir.
你认为我们什么时候可以开工
When do you think we'll be up and running?
我估计  1个月之内
Within a month, I'd say.
两周
Two weeks.
好  两周
Uh, yeah, two weeks.
很好  非常好
Good. Very good.
顺便说一声
By the way,
您让我检测的样品
that sample you asked me to run,
我测过了  品质非常好
I ran it, and it is quite good.
谢谢你  盖尔
Thank you very much, Gale.
剩下的可以交给维克多处理掉
You can give that to Victor to discard.
好的
Uh, sure.
那是我们的竞争对手的货吗
Is that our competition?
你说什么
I'm sorry?
那个
The, uh...
那个样品真的非常好
It really is quite good.
我指的是  纯度
The purity, of course, I'm speaking of,
化学范畴的"好"
speaking strictly in chemical terms.
迄今  我还不能确定为什么偏蓝
And I can't, as of yet, account for the blue color,
但是  如果那是我们的竞争对手
but, uh... if that is our competition,
那么可以说  我们的工作遇到了挑战
we have our work cut out for us, so to speak.
你没有任何竞争对手  盖尔
You don't have any competition, Gale,
至少在我关注范围没有
not as far as I'm concerned.
话说回来  再纯又能纯到哪里去
After all, how pure can pure be?
可以纯到匪夷所思
Well, it can be pretty darn pure.
福林先生  我向您保证可达96%的纯度
Mr. Fring, I can guarantee you a purity of 96%.
我为这数字骄傲
I'm proud of that figure.
这个96%来之不易
It's a hard-earned figure, 96.
可是  那个样本的纯度是99%
However, this other product is 99,
甚至可能更纯一点
maybe even a touch beyond that.
我需要一台气相色谱仪才能确定
I'd need an instrument called a gas chromatograph to say for sure,
3个百分点听起来好像不多
but, uh, that last 3%, it may not sound like a lot,
可是  那真的是
but, uh, but it is.
难以逾越
It's tremendous.
难以逾越的鸿沟
It's a tremendous gulf.
盖尔  就我们的目的来说
Gale, for our purposes,
96%已经足够了
96% will do just fine.
请你不要为这事烦心
Please, don't let this trouble you.
我懂  只是...
Yeah. It's just...
我想知道这是谁合成出来的
I'd love to know who synthesized it
就是这样
is all.
一个想跟我合作的人
A man who wants to work with me.
训练有素的化学家  像你一样
A trained chemist, like yourself.
但我们不会合作的
But it won't happen.
我认为他不够专业
I don't consider him a professional.
如果他还不专业  那我简直什么都不是
If he's not, I don't know what that makes me.
我不是说我不能胜任
I'm not trying to talk myself out of a job.
这个人有其它方面的问题
With this person, there are other considerations.
他的货是我见过的最棒的  毫无疑问
His is the best I've ever seen, hands down.
我看到你建这个地方
And I look at this place that you've built,
投资那么大
the money you're investing,
不惜血本
sparing no expense.
我知道
And I know...
我知道你想要最棒的
I know that you want the best.
第四季 第一集
S04E01: Box Cutter
胡安・塔布街  6353号
6353 Juan Tabo.
6单元
Apartment 6.
不  不尤班克路西边
No, no. Eubank's west.
在尤班克路和西班牙路之间
It's between Eubank and Spain,
离马萨特兰比较近
but Mazatlan's closest.
不知道  我只听到一声
I don't know. I just heard the one,
就一声  就是那种发动机逆火的声音
just the one single, like, you know, like a backfire,
像是卡车逆火
like a truck backfiring.
我就从公寓里出来
I came out of my apartment...
还有几个人也出来了
A couple of us came out.
没  没人目击
No. No, nobody saw it.
你们有看到什么人吗
Did you guys see anybody?
喂  有没有啊
Guys, did you?
我不知道他们是不是听得懂
I don't know if they speak English too good.
他们只是摇头
They're just shaking their heads.
我想他们没看见什么人
I don't think they saw anybody.
只听到一声巨响
It was just this one loud...
就是很响的  嘭的一声  然后就没动静了
this... this very loud pop, and that was all.
没听到争吵什么的
No arguing or like that.
你们认得路吗
So you guys good in directions there?
你让我...
You want me to...
他们打哪边来  东边还是西边
They coming east or west?
如果向东走
If they're heading east,
那他们的左手边会有一家埃克森石油
tell them there's an Exxon on their left-hand side.
直走就是住宅区
then it's straight residential.
你要我干什么  好
You want me to what? Yeah.
不  我在线等
No. I'll stay on the line.
你认得他
You know him?
我们都听到了枪声
We all heard this shot.
我说  你不应过去
Hey, I don't think you ought to go in there.
先生  这可是罪案现场
Mister, this is a crime scene.
不能碰任何东西
You don't want to touch anything.
先生
Mister...
先生  你有没听到我说话
Mister, are you listening to me?
你这小杂种
You little bastard.
开车
Drive.
快开车
Drive!
到底怎么回事
What the hell happened?
人死了
He's gone?
看着我
Look at me.
死了
Gone?
你确定
You sure?
死了
Gone?
血肉横飞
Splattered all over.
老天爷
Oh, Jesus.
靠
Oh, shit.
行啊
All right.
那么
So...
靠
Shit.
清理现场了没
All right, you do a sweep?
不行  有人在
I couldn't. People there.
有人
People?
有人看见他死在那儿了
He get himself seen by these people?
那你呢
What about you?
你有没有被看见
有  怎么样
Yeah. So what?
也就一两眼
Just another looky-loo.
我看我最好处理下
I guess I'd better get this over with.
对不起  我把你吵醒了
Oh, geez, I-- I-- I woke you up.
-我把你吵醒了  -不不不  没事的
- I woke you up. - No, no, no. It's okay.
我本来也要起床了
I needed to get up anyway.
进来吗
Are you coming in?
不用了  我就这点时间能出来办事
No, no. It's kind of my only time to run errands.
我只是想
I just needed to-- Ah.
我
I--
对不起
Sorry.
没关系
It's okay.
我们一直都非常感谢你
And thank you, big time, as always.
账单不仅没有减少  好像反而越积越多
They seem to be getting bigger instead of smaller,
我也不太清楚怎么回事
and I'm not really sure what that's all about.
看在上帝的份上
Please, for God's sake,
告诉我是不是太为难你们了
tell me if this is getting to be too much for you guys.
没有的事  好吗
Absolutely not, okay?
完全没问题
It's absolutely fine.
好吧
Okay.
我没有想错吧
Does this mean what I think it means?
什么
What?
你和沃尔特
You and Walt?
怎么了
What?
他的车就停在门前车道上呢
His car's parked in the driveway.
谁都看得见
It's not a state secret.
我...我不是给你压力哈
I-- uh, all right. Okay. I'm not pressing.
只是
I just--
我觉得这挺好
I think that it's great.
就这样吧
That's all, all right?
-我走了  -好的
- I'm out of here. - Okay.
替我跟假装不在先生问声好
A big howdy-do to Mr. I'm-Not-Here.
吃早餐吗
Breakfast?
好
Yeah.
我来做
Yeah? Okay.
想吃什么
All right. What do you want?
好吧   听我说
All right, look.
已经8点50了  所以
So I make it 10 to 9, which means--
闭上嘴
Shut up.
所以我们得在10分钟内做起来
Which means we need to start a cook in the next 10 minutes
才能赶上我们的计划
to keep to our schedule--
古斯的计划
Gus' schedule.
不管他现在怎么生气
And as angry as he may be,
我想他不会愿意这样放弃整批货
I don't believe he's willing to forfeit an entire batch.
那只会惹他更生气
That just might make him angrier.
别这样  麦克  让我们干活吧
Come on, Mike. Let us cook.
这一切不都是为了这个
Isn't that what this whole thing is about?
说的没错  天才  看好我
That's right, genius. Watch me.
我们不会耽误进度的
We ain't missing no cook.
我们打烊了  打烊了
We're closed. Closed.
索尔・古德曼律师事务所
Saul Goodman and Associates.
我看看他在不在  请别挂
I'll see if he's in. Please hold.
索尔  斯凯勒・怀特找你
Saul, Skyler White calling.
索尔
Saul.
索尔  斯凯勒・怀特打电话来了
Saul, Skyler White on the line.
索尔
Saul!
斯凯勒・怀特
Skyler White.
她想干嘛
What the hell does she want?
我找不到他
Uh, h-he's nowhere to be found.
我打到他家里
I called his condo.
他所有号码我都打过了
I called every number I have for him.
我肯定他没事
Yeah, I'm sure he's fine.
你肯定
You're sure?
你知道他在哪
As in you know where he is?
我不是他保姆
Well, I'm not the man's keeper,
但沃尔特是个大人了
but, uh, Walt's a big boy.
他会出现的
He'll turn up.
古德曼先生  很明显出了问题
Mr. Goodman, clearly something is going on here.
他会把车停在我家车道上吗
I mean, why would he leave his car in my driveway?
现在人拼车上班
People carpool to work, right?
对环境有好处嘛
It's good for the environment.
拼车
He carpools?
他和人拼车去毒品实验室
He carpools to his job at a meth lab?
你断线了呀
Hey, whoa! Ho ho! You're breaking up there.
最后说什么我没听清
I didn't quite catch that last-- Whoo!
你今天真能侃
You're a chatty Cathy today.
好吧  你知道点什么吗
Okay, do you know anything?
什么都行  拜托你
Anything at all? Please!
请你帮帮忙
I'm looking for some help here.
听着  沃尔特没事  好吗
Look, Walter is fine, okay?
我百分百保证
I guarantee that 100%.
百分百个头
100%.
你有护照的吧
You got a passport, right?
嗯  阿尔布开克
Yeah. Uh, Albuquerque.
我这里是诺布山
I'm in, uh, Nob Hill.
我要找个锁匠
I need the number for a locksmith.
不知道  随便吧
I don't know. Pick one.
真的没办法吗
You sure there's nothing?
不是我不帮你
No, it's not even me.
法律不允许呀
It's state law, really.
你就没有点什么
Are you sure there isn't some sort of,
证明之类的
I don't know, um--
没有  真没有
No. Nothing.
车辆登记也许可以
Maybe, uh, a car registration.
上面应该有您家地址
That would have your address.
可我现在车都进不去
No, but I can't even get in my car.
我车钥匙和门钥匙挂在一起
My car keys were on the same ring.
天哪  我的信用卡
My God, my-- my-- my credit cards,
别哭  小宝贝
my-- It's all right, sweetheart.
我的驾照  支票簿
My driver's license, my checkbook.
我必须去全部注销掉
I have to start canceling all that--
我什么都装在钱包里了
My whole life was in that purse,
他就这么施施然来  轻飘飘就偷走了
and he just came, and he cut it right off my shoulder.
幸好我们母女没有遭其毒手
We could have been stabbed.
真遗憾  真的
I'm sorry, really.
但没有居住证明
But without proof of residency--
不然去我店里吧
I can take you down to my shop.
可以在那安坐等待  填妥警方笔录
You're welcome to wait there, file a police report.
真不敢相信
I can't believe this.
今天怎么这么倒霉
I cannot believe this day.
我知道  只是...
I know. It's just...
规定就是规定
the law.
天
Oh, my God.
我的身份证  不见了
My identification. It's gone.
上帝啊  别再这样了啊
Oh, God, not-- not this second.
打电话给药店  我...
Call the pharmacy. I--
你还好吧
Are you okay?
拜托  抱下她
Please, just-- Please, just take her.
帮我抱下她  拜托了
Just take her, please.
天哪
Oh. Oh, God.
别是现在啊
Not now.
不要啊
No. No. No.
你救了我的命啊  真的
Oh, you're a lifesaver. Truly.
好啦  宝贝
Here you go, sweetheart.
好了好了
Oh, there you go.
请问
Um, how do you, um,
请问账单怎么付
how do you want to deal with the bill?
真不幸  我的现金也被偷光光了
I-- Unfortunately, all my cash was taken, so--
没事  我们寄给你
That's fine. We'll mail it to you.
真的  知道我地址吗
Will you? You do know where I live, right?
先生  再次感谢  太谢谢了
Sir, again, thank you so much.
真的
Really. Yeah.
嘿  我回来了
Hey, there! I'm back!
物理治疗如何
How was P.T.?
听说效果很好
I heard it was very good.
是啊
Yeah.
我很喜欢新治疗师
I'm really liking this new therapist.
他跟我保持着联系
He keeps me in the loop,
能时时跟我通电话
always has time for a phone call.
很不错
I just-- I like it.
那么
So...
来说说看
tell me all about it.
听说你今天有新突破
I heard you broke new ground today.
是吗
I broke new ground?
他是这么说的
That's what he said.
说说看呢
Tell me.
我20分钟走了16英尺[约5米]
I walked 16 feet in 20 minutes,
确实比昨天多了半英尺
which is up from my 15 1/2 yesterday.
还少拉了点在裤子上
And I had maybe this much less shit in my pants,
玛丽  如果你和他
so yeah, Marie, if you and him
还有其他美国人已秘密投票
and everybody else in America secretly took a vote
决定颠覆所有英文的意思
and changed the meaning of the entire English language,
那我想应该是突破吧
yeah, I guess I broke new ground.
好吧  这是比喻好不好
Well, call it a figure of speech,
但我确实看到了进步啊
but I am seeing progress.
绝对的进步
Definite progress.
你要买新岩石吗
You're ordering a new rock?
我在竞拍新矿石
I'm bidding on a new mineral.
这块很美
It's a nice one.
怎么了  确实很美啊
What? It's pretty.
我要上厕所
I need the thing.
好
Okay.
大的小的
Numero uno?
大的
Dos.
好
Okay.
那些
Those--
那些漂亮的小晶体  我很喜欢
Those pretty little crystals. I like that.
好了
Okay.
好吧  容我提醒一下
All right, I just want to go on record
我们该戴上防护罩
we should all be wearing masks.
都该戴上防护罩
We should be wearing masks.
我敢说他忘记放铝粉了
I bet he forgets the aluminum.
我敢担保
Guaranteed.
他一准忘记
Guarantee he forgets.
都不知道自己在做什么  是吧
Oh, you don't know what the hell you're doing, do you?
你刚放铝粉了
You forgot the aluminum.
其中第一步是
One of the first steps in the--
该死的
Son of a bitch.
好了  该谈谈盖尔・伯蒂彻了
All right, let's talk about Gale Boetticher.
他是个好人  好制毒师
He was a good man and a good chemist,
我很喜欢他
and I cared about him.
他本不该有如此下场的
He didn't deserve what happened to him.
罪不至此
He didn't deserve it at all.
但我还是迟早
But I'd shoot him again tomorrow
会亲手枪杀了他的
and the next day and the day after that.
如果你在我和盖尔
When you make it Gale versus me
或者杰西和盖尔之间择一
or Gale versus Jesse,
他必输无疑  就这么简单
Gale loses, simple as that.
这都因你而起 古斯
This is on you, Gus--
不因我  也不因杰西
not me, not Jesse.
盖尔的死是因你而起的
Gale's death is on you.
不然你还指望我怎么做
I mean, really, what did you expect me to do,
就这么认输
just simply roll over
让你毙了我们吗
and allow you to murder us?
我不该采取行动
That I wouldn't take measures--
甚至是极端行动来保护自己吗
extreme measures to defend myself?
错
Wrong!
再想想
Think again.
不管怎样
And whatever--
不管你在打算些什么
whatever it is you're planning there,
不管是什么
whatever-- whatever it is--
不管你想达到什么目标
the point that you're trying to make here,
容我提醒一句  你要知道一件事
let me-- let me suggest that you keep one thing in mind.
没有我们
Without us,
没有杰西和我
without Jesse and myself,
就没人能帮你制毒
you have no one to make your product.
当然他更不能
Certainly not him.
他根本不知道自己在做什么
This person doesn't know what the hell he's doing!
我观察了他好几周
Been watching him for weeks.
知道了他制毒的每个步骤
I know every step of his cook.
真的吗  你...
Do you really? You--
真的  那请告诉我
Really? Oh, so please tell me.
催化氢化作用是质子还是无质子反应
Catalytic hydrogenation, is it protic or aprotic?
因为我忘记了
Because I forget.
如果你的提纯不是立体定向的
And if our reduction is not stereospecific,
你怎么能确定成品的纯度
then how can our product be enantiomerically pure?
一个苯基  一个羟基
I mean, is 1 phenyl, 1 hyrdoxyl,
两个甲胺基
2 methylamino propane--
当然还包括丙烷链中
containing, of course, chiral centers
一号和二号碳原子这两个手性中心
at carbons number 1 and 2 on the propane chain.
那如果提纯至甲基苯丙胺[冰毒]
Then reduction to Methamphetamine
又该减去哪个手征性中心呢
eliminates which chiral center is it again?
因为我都忘记了
Because I forgot.
说啊  帮帮我啊  教授
Come on, help me out, professor!
古斯
Gus.
算了吧  我们在这里
We're here. Come on.
让我们干活吧
Let us work.
说的都是废话  那叫制毒
All his bullshit aside, it's called a cook.
要按照配方做每一件事
See, everything comes down to following a recipe.
是简单还是复杂  都无所谓
Simple, complicated, it doesn't matter.
步骤一成不变
The steps never change,
我知道所有的步骤
and I know every step.
这就是你想要的吗
Oh, is-- is that what you want?
这种劣质产品
This... short order cook?
这跟做汉堡不一样  老兄
You're not fpping hamburgers here, pal.
如果你的原材料有问题怎么办
What happens when you get a bad barrel of precursor?
你甚至都不会鉴别
Or how would you even know it?
到了夏季
And what happens in the summer
湿度升高
when the humidity rises
你的货受潮了怎么办
and your product goes cloudy?
你有什么防范措施呢
H-How would you guard against that?
古斯
Gus.
如果你这么做
You do this,
只会给你
all you'll have left
造成八百万元的经济损失
is an $8 million hole in the ground.
没有我们
This lab--
这间实验室  这些设备都是摆设
This equipment is useless without us.
没有杰西和我
Without Jesse and myself,
你就没有新产品
you have no new product.
你就没有收入
You have no income.
你的手下就得不到工钱
Your people out there will not be paid.
你的分销渠道就会崩溃
Your distribution chain collapses.
没有我们
Without us...
你会一无所有
you have nothing.
你杀了我  就断了财路
You kill me, you have nothing.
你杀了杰西  也就失去了我
You kill Jesse, you don't have me.
你不会这样做的
You won't do this.
你是个聪明人
You're too smart.
你承受不了这代价
You can't afford to do this.
求你了
Please.
让我们继续干活
Let us just go back to work.
我们就在这里
We're here.
让我们干活吧
Let us work.
我们准备好要干活了
We're ready to go to work.
我们接着之前的进度继续干
We'll just pick up right where we left off.
愣着干嘛
Well?
接着干活
Get back to work.
把这个捅放平
Let's just-- We'll just lay this down.
先把脚装进去
We'll put him in feet first.
抓着他的鞋
Grab his shoe.
等一等  把他抬起来
Oh. Here. Wait, wait. Just lift him up.
好了
There. All right.
就这样
Here we go.
天呐
God.
你往里推  我扶着他
If you push that way, I'll hold him in.
好的  准备好没
Okay, ready?
一
1--
该死的
Oh, shit!
好了  等一等
All right, wait. Wait.
别管它了
Forget that.
用力
Come on.
抬起来
Up!
放下
Get down.
好了
Okay.
氢氟酸
(HYDROFLUORIC ACID)
我从没用过这玩意  能管用吗
I never used this stuff. You sure it'll do the job?
相信我们
Trust us.
腐蚀剂
(CORROSIVE)
给你  亲  还需要什么吗
Here you go, hon. Get you anything else?
不用了  谢谢
Uh, no, I'm good. Thanks.
你好吗
How are you doing?
我的意思是...
No, I mean, you know--
你感觉还好吗
How are you doing?
你做了你唯一能做的
You did the only thing that you could.
我希望你能明白这一点
I hope you understand that.
有什么打算
Thoughts?
你是说
Got any thoughts
下一步我们有什么打算吗
on what our next move might be?
什么下一步
What next move?
我们的下一步
Our next move.
Our next move,
鉴于古斯一旦有机会就会干掉我们
given the fact that at the first opportunity Gus will kill us.
难道刚才不是干掉我们的好机会吗
What, that wasn't an opportunity just now?
我感觉那机会他妈非常好
Seemed like a pretty damn good opportunity to me.
-不是的  -我说那是黄金机会
-No, no. - Golden, I would say.
我们为自己争取了些时间
We bought ourselves some time.
没错  不过...
Yes, but--
问题是多久
the question is how much.
他一定在寻找接替我的人
He'll be looking for another chemist.
他不会找到能够接替你的人
He's not going to find another chemist.
他上哪去找接替你的人呢
Where is he going to find another chemist?
这个人不仅要有能力
It's not just about somebody
使这么大的实验室正常运转
being able to run a lab that big.
还要值得信任
Someone he can trust,
他得确保这个人会守口如瓶
someone he knows will keep their mouths shut.
对  祝他好运
Yeah. Good luck with that.
估计他用了很多年才找到盖尔
Bet it took him years to find Gale.
他现在一定很伤心
Bet he's sorry now.
你确定自己没事吗
Are you sure you're okay?
至少现在我们能互相理解
At least now we all understand each other.
对吧
Right?
你这话什么意思
What do you mean?
意思是我们上了他的贼船
I mean him and us, we get it.
我们现在同坐一条船
We're all on the same page.
这又是条什么船呢
What page is that?
这条船上的人说...
The one that says...
即使我杀不了你
if I can't kill you,
你他妈也别想活得舒服
you'll sure as s--- wish you were dead.
打扰一下
Yo. Excuse me.
谢谢
Thanks.
给你
Here.
谢谢
Thanks.
嗨
Hi.
我把车停到安士敦街了
It's parked over on Amsden.
小怀特要起床了  我怕他看到
Junior was about to get up, and he would have seen it,
我不想让他东问西问的
so I wanted to avoid a lot of questions.
很聪明
That was smart.
是啊
Yeah.
肯尼・罗格斯的T恤[美国歌手]
Kenny Rogers.
你没事吧
You okay?
没事
Yeah.
我好得很
Right as rain.
你带钥匙了吗
Do you have your keys?
带了
Yeah.
车停在三个街区外
Uh, it's parked three blocks down
马路右边
on the right.
好的
Yeah.